<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>raspberry pi on Karthik Mahendra</title>
    <link>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/tags/raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in raspberry pi on Karthik Mahendra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ikarthikmb.github.io/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi 4 with Heatsink</title>
      <link>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/wallpaper/rpired_wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/wallpaper/rpired_wall/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up Raspberry Pi 4(Wi-Fi)</title>
      <link>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/posts/rpi4_setup_wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 01:59:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/posts/rpi4_setup_wifi/</guid>
      <description>Contents
 Hardware Requirements: Steps to install the required software tools  Further Steps:   Accessing Pi Desktop Remotely   The set up for Raspberry Pi using Wi-Fi is the same as the previous article on how to Set Up Raspberry Pi 4 through laptop/pc using Ethernet cable(No Moniter, No Wi-Fi) with some minor changes which we are going to see.
Hardware Requirements:  Raspberry Pi 4 Model B (1/2/4 GB RAM) USB Type-C power supply Personal computer  Steps to install the required software tools  If you had followed the previous article then skip these steps and move to &amp;lsquo;step-6&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intruder Detection Using Pi Camera</title>
      <link>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/projects/ultrasonic_rpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/projects/ultrasonic_rpi/</guid>
      <description>Contents
 Hardware Circuit Connection The Code Youtube Video Tutorial:   This project is about capturing the pictures of strangers through the Pi Camera attached to Raspberry Pi. This is a DIY project which can detect people using the motion sensor(PIR sensor) by capturing a photo whenever the motion is detected.
Hardware  Raspberry Pi 2/3/4 Pi Camera PIR Sensor Jumpers  Circuit Connection 
Connect the PIR sensor to raspberry pi as shown in the above circuit diagram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Up Raspberry Pi 4 through laptop/pc using Ethernet cable(No Monitor, No Wi-Fi)</title>
      <link>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/posts/rpi4_setup_w_ethernet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 01:59:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/posts/rpi4_setup_w_ethernet/</guid>
      <description>Contents
 Hardware Requirements: Steps to install the required software tools  Step-1: OS Download Step-2: Imager Step-3: SSH Client Download Step-4: Real VNC Viewer Step-5: Image Burning Step-6: ssh Step-7: Power Step-8: Network Connections Step-9: SSH Configuration Step-10: Authentication Step-11: Pi Terminal   Accessing Pi Desktop Remotely   In this we shall be working with Raspberry Pi 4 Model-B of 1Gb RAM for the set up. Raspberry-Pi is a single board computer used for educational purposes and DIY projects with an affordable cost, requires a power supply of 5 volts with 3 amps current.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Soil Moisture using Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/projects/soil_moisture_rpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ikarthikmb.github.io/projects/soil_moisture_rpi/</guid>
      <description>Do you know how often to water plants? Or outpoured plants and lost them. To solve this I thought it would be more circumstantial if we can get the value of water content inside the soil in order to make a decision for watering the plants appropriately.
In this project lets try to build a circuit which can measure the water content value of the soil eventually control the flow using Raspberry Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
